hi there today we are going to talk
你好，今天我们要谈
about a little about Carla and Jane
关于卡拉和简的一些事
oseco and cloud and how we can use it to
oseco和云，以及我们如何使用它来
actually solve problems that's why we
真正解决问题，这就是为什么我们
are here we are more much more than just
在这里，我们不仅仅是
programmers just to using tools and so
程序员只是为了使用工具等
on but we are here to solve problems and
继续，但是我们在这里解决问题，
what I've just built here in this
我刚刚在这里建立的
presentation is using some kind of chose
演示文稿正在使用某种选择
to their I like it - there are useful
对他们我喜欢-有帮助
tools they are very made let's say
他们说的非常好的工具
famous today to actually solve problems
今天出名，真正解决问题
so let's go to presentation and enjoy it
因此，让我们去演示并享受它
well when were thinking about a kind of
好吧，当正在考虑一种
problem that I would like to solve use
我想解决使用的问题
some different tools that we discussed
我们讨论了一些不同的工具
today I imagine a recommendation
今天我想像一个建议
application who could make
谁可以申请
recommendation software where for
推荐软件在哪里
example I would have a developer
例子我会有一个开发人员
resource - developer in this developer
资源-此开发人员中的开发人员
has like or or enjoy or no or domain
有喜欢，喜欢或不喜欢或没有域
some kind of language and this language
某种语言和这种语言
he or her remain in some level ok so
他或她保持在一定水平，所以
advanced said regular medium or beginner
高级表示常规中级或初学者
and this developer lives in some sea so
这个开发者住在海里
for example I elder I am a Java
例如我长大我是Java
developer and talking about Java and
开发人员并讨论Java和
advanced it but for example I know a
先进，但例如我知道
little about go
很少去
but for go I am a beginner and I live in
但对于我来说，我是一个初学者，我住在
Sao Paulo
圣保罗
most of time but I also spend a lot of
大多数时间，但我也花了很多
time in the year in San Francisco so
一年中在旧金山的时间
maybe I could add San Francisco here so
也许我可以在这里加旧金山
the point the robit
关键点
of the application is sign me out some
的应用程序正在将我注销
recommendations related to the
有关的建议
technologies that are like or I would
类似或我会的技术
like to work with so for example if I'm
喜欢一起工作，例如，如果我
in Sao Paulo I would like that this to
我想在圣保罗
this application that I'm about to
我将要使用的这个应用程序
develop choose send me recommendations
开发选择给我发送建议
related to Java and maybe some other
与Java有关，也许还有其他一些
people work with Java in diversity level
人们在多样性级别上使用Java
or just Java on itself and maybe people
或者只是Java本身，也许还有人
that I work with Java and live in Sao
我使用Java并住在圣地
Paulo or live in San Francisco or maybe
Paulo或住在旧金山，也许
in the neighbor areas of this both
在这两个的邻近地区
cities ok so let's go ahead and
好的城市，让我们继续前进，
presentation see some tools that we can
演示文稿中看到了一些我们可以使用的工具
use for that and how they can work
使用它以及它们如何工作
together so the first tool that I've
在一起，所以我的第一个工具
chosen to for our problem that we would
选择解决我们的问题
like to solve
喜欢解决
it's Jakarta II and not just because I
这是雅加达II，而不仅仅是因为我
like Jakarta but is because it is very
像雅加达一样，但是因为它非常
powerful very useful and I have been
强大非常有用，我一直
using it for a long long time even
甚至长时间使用
before HIV well why'd you carry well
在感染艾滋病毒之前，你为什么要好好携带
let's first think about why Jakari is
首先考虑一下为什么贾卡里是
not that some people think that it is
不是有人认为这是
that since Java Java is dead your curry
由于Java Java已死，您的咖喱
is that's not used for anymore
不再使用了
well I would say for you that we have
好吧，我会为您说，我们有
still many many publications have been
仍然有很多出版物
published yet for Ricardo HIV I myself
我自己为里卡多艾滋病毒发表的文章
had a book about Java eh
有一本关于Java的书
we still have a lot of developers and
我们仍然有很多开发人员，
other world one of the most used
其他世界中最常用的之一
frameworks in the whole world shove a
全世界的框架推
year or Akari right now with the new
一年或Akari现在与新
name we still have a lot of career
名字我们还有很多职业
opportunities if when I work with
与我共事的机会
Shikari in
鹿里
you are good at it you still have not
你擅长它，你还没有
allow a lot of opportunities love
允许很多机会的爱
positions open in the market in the
在市场上开设仓位
industry well as a specification there
工业以及那里的规范
are a lot of compatible application
有很多兼容的应用程序
servers so you have a lot of choices and
服务器，所以您有很多选择，
if you're the company that you are
如果你是你的公司
working or would like to work are using
工作或想工作的人正在使用
one kind of application server and the
一种应用服务器和
other has another choice you can work
别人还有另一种选择可以工作
with both of them because you know
与他们两个，因为你知道
specification it has a standard so you
规范它有一个标准，所以你
can build the application for the
可以为
standards and of course there are there
标准，当然有
are a lot of user groups around the
周围有很多用户组
world working with Jakari contributing
与Jakari合作的世界
to the specifications and can evolve it
到规格并可以发展
so yet it's a vibrant community the verb
所以这是一个充满活力的社区
and technology framework and there's a
和技术框架，还有一个
lot of things happening and if you think
很多事情正在发生，如果你认为
about the companies that is using Jacare
关于使用Jacare的公司
each day nowadays I have a couple of
如今，每天我有几个
examples
例子
in this slide and this one are companies
在这张幻灯片中，这是公司
there that publicly has said that they
那里有公开说过
are using Jacare of course just a few of
当然正在使用Jacare
them but for that you have an idea of
他们，但为此你有一个想法
how much companies and how big they are
有多少公司，有多少
how small also as more companies also
还有多小的公司
use
采用
Jakari but here we had a couple of
贾卡里（Jakari），但在这里我们有几个
examples companies using jakarta ii i'm
示例公司使用jakarta ii
sure that most of you already know that
确保你们大多数人已经知道
in 2017 Orrico has announced ended the
2017年，Orrico宣布终止
it was transferring java if by that time
如果那个时候它正在转移Java
to eclipse foundation Java
使基础Java黯然失色
yes was already an open-source project
是的，已经是一个开源项目
but this movement to Eclipse Foundation
但是这个运动到了Eclipse基金会
has a lot of implications
有很多影响
really
真
to open-source now ending the the point
开源现在结束了这一点
is to have a very much more open much
要开放得多
more balanced the the between the all
所有之间的更加平衡
the people the all the stakeholders work
人民，所有利益相关者的工作
with your car here we have much more
有了你的车，我们还有更多
balanced than before so for example
比以前平衡，例如
talking about road map what's being
谈论路线图是什么
moving from Oracle to eclipse foundation
从Oracle迁移到Eclipse基础
basically the specifications the API is
基本上是API的规格
the the reference implementation and it
参考实现及其
is scale with the frame the test
与框架成比例测试
framework all those parts are being
构架所有这些部分
transferred from to eclipse foundation
从转移到日食基金会
and what won't be transferred is a
不会被转移的是
trademark basically that's why we need
商标基本上就是这就是为什么我们需要
to change the name from Java each or
分别从Java更改名称或
Jakara II so that's the body
Jakara II所以就是身体
transferring process and if you are
转移过程，如果你是
asking about the the status that we have
询问我们的状态
today it's the the image was taking just
今天是图片拍摄的
today and this is the position okay now
今天，这是现在的位置
we are in second May so if you if you're
我们在五月二号，如果您
if you've seen this graph you can see
如果您看过此图，您可以看到
that almost all projects has already its
几乎所有项目都已经
first readies review we have here all
首先准备回顾，我们都在这里
the the milestones for each parts 20
每个部分的里程碑20
percent 4 percent 60 percent 80 percent
％4％60％80％
and you can see here that the jacory
你可以在这里看到
platform is in the 80 percent so he had
平台占80％，所以他有
over the initial contribution to the git
超过对git的初始贡献
repository so maybe here we have missing
仓库，所以也许我们在这里失踪了
just some kind of IP transferring and so
只是某种IP传输等等
on okay and other projects like Jakarta
还可以，例如雅加达
batch Jakara Gino psycho Jakarta Lucy
批Jakara Gino心理学家雅加达露西
cough sorry the first project that has
咳嗽对不起第一个有
born already in under the
已经出生在
Eclipse Foundation project for jacquard
提花的Eclipse Foundation项目
II well so if you think about the the
我很好，所以如果你考虑
some kind of name how they can have
他们如何拥有某种名字
changing from work or to eclipse
从工作或日食转变
foundation so for example we had glass
基础，例如，我们有玻璃
fish that is now eclipsed GlassFish we
现在已经黯然失色的鱼GlassFish
had the former JCP in Java community
在Java社区中拥有前JCP
process that has not ended it still
尚未结束的过程
exists it's the stewardship over all the
存在，这是对所有
Java SE projects specifications the
Java SE项目规范
equivalents from JCP to eclipse
等价于JCP到eclipse
foundation we had now the Jakara a
我们现在拥有的基础Jakara a
working group that is working on all
正在全体工作的​​工作组
those aspects from Jakarta a project and
雅加达的一个项目
what was calling or called the Oracle
被称为或称为甲骨文的东西
development management now we have the
开发管理现在我们有了
Eclipse Enterprise for Java there's the
Eclipse Enterprise for Java有
project umbrella for Jakarta and we had
雅加达的项目伞，我们有
also the project management committee or
也是项目管理委员会或
the PMC at the group that is leading all
领导所有团队的PMC
these projects all the groups all the
这些项目所有小组
the specifications for Jakarta II we
雅加达II的规格我们
can't say we can't talk today about Java
不能说我们今天不能谈论Java
Enterprise without talking about micro
企业不谈微
profile because we are in the micro
简介，因为我们在微观
service error page we are in the days
我们过去的服务错误页面
that everybody is talking about micro
每个人都在谈论微
servers in some way and Java developers
服务器和Java开发人员
we can't stay behind who can't stay all
我们不能留在谁不能留所有的人后面
of this conversation and we have the
这次谈话，我们有
right tool for that that is micro
微型的正确工具
profile a micro profile was born from
微型档案是从中诞生的
Java EE as an optimization for to press
Java EE作为印刷的优化
Java in the way that we think about
Java的思考方式
micro service so yes it's an
微服务，是的，这是一个
optimization for to preserve for
为保留而优化
Microsoft's architecture and the point
微软的架构和重点
here is have to a much more faster pace
这必须要快得多
so they talked a lot about no wait so
所以他们谈论了很多没有等待的事情
the fire readies and repeat so it's a
火准备并重复，所以这是一个
cycle
周期
where you have much more a kind of MVP
你有更多的MVP
approach in the way that we once we have
我们曾经拥有的方式
a feature working and compatible and
工作正常且兼容的功能
specification way we can then release it
规范方式，然后我们可以释放它
and then we will go back and innovate
然后我们会回去创新
and get this innovation certified and
并获得这项创新认证
release and repeat and so on so yeah
释放并重复等等，是的
record profile it's the way of doing
记录个人资料是这样做的方式
Java Enterprise for micro service and in
适用于微服务和in的Java Enterprise
our problem that we are trying to solve
我们试图解决的问题
the accommodation system for our
我们的住宿系统
developers working technology and living
开发人员从事技术和生活
cities it's very useful to have macro
城市拥有宏非常有用
profile as approach for Java EE in a
概要文件作为Java EE的方法
micro services way so there is some
微服务的方式，所以有一些
specification that was born under the
在
micro profile project so we have here
微型配置文件项目，所以我们在这里
config half-shark matrix photo learners
配置半鲨鱼矩阵照片学习者
rest clients open api j WT and OPA
其余客户端打开api j WT和OPA
tracing of then we're born under the
追踪，然后我们出生在
macro profile and there there were
宏观资料，那里
others aps that were brought from Java
Java带来的其他aps
for example jax-rs CGI and so on so yes
例如jax-rs CGI等，是的
we are talking about huge plication
我们正在谈论巨大的恳求
split asia that we recommend developers
我们推荐开发者来划分亚洲
for each other that we recommend people
为彼此推荐的人
and we today talk about massive data
今天我们谈论海量数据
massive more of the that are being
大量的
communicating to the cloud between the
之间的云通信
and applications and service and around
以及应用程序和服务以及周围
so yes today it's very makes a lot of
所以是的，今天很多
sense to talk about no sequel databases
谈论没有续集数据库的感觉
because especially women think about
因为尤其是女性思考
micro servers we have all those micro
微型服务器，我们拥有所有这些微型
service spreaded and different networks
服务分散和不同的网络
different technologies and so on so the
不同的技术等等
the kind of consistency that we have any
我们所拥有的那种一致性
database is not what we were used in the
数据库不是我们在
monolith way so it makes sense to talk
整体的方式，所以说话很有意义
about no Seco when we are talking about
我们谈论的时候没有山高
these kind of applications so when we
这些应用程序，所以当我们
think about no Seco we should say we
想想没有山高，我们应该说我们
can't say also of course there is a
当然也不能说
database usually it doesn't have a
数据库通常没有
structure in most of cases we don't have
在大多数情况下我们没有结构
a transaction there are some discussions
交易中有一些讨论
about getting have some kind of
关于获得某种
transaction and no secret of the base
交易，基地没有秘密
but nowadays you can say that there is
但是现在你可以说
no section the way that we think about
没有一节我们思考的方式
data in no Seco it's the base way where
No Seco中的数据是其中的基本方式
we can say that the database is
我们可以说数据库是
basically available we you you can
基本上可用，我们可以
affirm that it's always available this
确认它始终可用
state it's not so not so strong in the
声明它不是那么强大
way that we think about it in relational
我们在关系中思考的方式
database and the consistency is eventual
数据库，最终一致性
so in some some points that the data
所以在某些方面，数据
will be consistent but its eventual okay
将保持一致，但最终还可以
and we have five different types of no
我们有五种不同的否
security base that we will discuss right
我们将讨论的安全基础
here so in in this Louis in the the
在这里在这路易
right side you can see a different some
右边你可以看到另外一些
kind of examples of no sequel database
无续集数据库的例子
so the first kind of gnostic
所以第一种不可知论者
the basis the K value on where basically
K值基本上以
we have a key in the well it's a prayer
我们在井里有一把钥匙，这是祈祷
so here we have a bolo and Sun we have
所以在这里，我们有一个bolo，而我们有Sun
here errors and war and we have wafer
这里有错误和战争，我们有晶圆
dyed with love and beauty so it's a key
充满爱与美丽，所以这是关键
value kind of data the most simple kind
重视数据最简单的一种
of data the other kind of those secure
数据的另一种安全
database that we have is column value
我们拥有的数据库是列值
mini so for example but really talking
迷你，例如，但真的在说话
about columns so we have the rocky and
关于列，所以我们有坎the的
the columns for example here we have
例如这里的列
Apollo if the duty Sun we have for diet
阿波罗如果我们有节食太阳
with the Duty loving happy and color is
与责任爱快乐和色彩是
pink and we have areas with the reward
粉红色，我们有奖励的地区
and we have different columns for if we
如果我们有不同的列
would like to for example we have kratos
想例如我们有kratos
and that not duty we have that guts 13
那不是义务，我们有胆量13
and you have the weapon word so we can
你有武器这个词，所以我们可以
mix the columns for each row key another
混合各行键的列
kind of database no secret oasis
那种数据库没有秘密绿洲
document and basically it's a json for
文档，基本上是一个json
each each document we can store so here
我们可以存储的每个文档都在这里
we have diana with duty hunt move in
我们有戴安娜（Diana）随身携带
nature and her siblings is the polar
大自然和她的兄弟姐妹是极地
Apollo and the is brother and we have
阿波罗和那个是兄弟，我们有
the graph databases where we have much
我们有很多图数据库
more complex kind of relationships so
更复杂的关系
for example I can say that Apollo was
例如，我可以说阿波罗是
killed by kratos and that cradles killed
被kratos杀死，摇篮被杀死
Apollo the same four areas and we have
阿波罗（Apollo）同样的四个区域
here another relationship between Apollo
这是阿波罗之间的另一种关系
in Aries and siblings and I can't say
在白羊和兄弟姐妹中，我不能说
that every skilled Kratos because of
每个熟练的Kratos都因为
course it was killed and we have
当然它被杀死了，我们有
another kind of relationship and in the
另一种关系
the graphs that we have properties in
我们在其中具有属性的图
the relationships so that's the
关系，所以
different way to see data relationships
查看数据关系的不同方法
in the graph database so and we have
在图形数据库中，所以我们有
also the mooch model no secure database
还有mooch模型没有安全的数据库
so for example and the orient DB is
因此，例如，东方数据库是
graph and document the Couchbase
绘制并记录Couchbase
implements key weather and document a
实施关键天气并记录
remedy be implements column family graph
补救是实施列族图
and key value any last search implements
和任何最后搜索实现的键值
the document and graph ok and we think
文档和图形确定，我们认为
if you think about the complexity and
如果您考虑复杂性和
scalability for this kind of North
这种北方的可扩展性
Dakota base we can have this this graph
达科他州基地，我们可以有这个图
so for example the key value has the
例如，键值具有
less complexity but it scales a lot in
复杂程度较低，但可以扩展很多
the other extreme we have the graph that
另一个极端，我们有图
has a lot of complexity but less
具有很多复杂性，但更少
scalability and we fee free compared
可扩展性，我们比较免费
relationship databases it would be just
关系数据库那将仅仅是
in the middle of graph and document
在图形和文档中间
little less complexity than graph and a
复杂度比图形少一点
little more scalability but less than
多一点可扩展性但少于
document databases and well as you just
文档数据库以及您
saw when we think about no security base
当我们考虑没有安全基础时看到
there's a lot of different approaches a
有很多不同的方法
lot of different ways of dealing with
许多不同的处理方式
data and but you know as a developer if
数据，但作为开发人员您知道
you would like to work with these
你想和这些一起工作
different though secure database it
与安全数据库不同
would be a pain because each database if
会很痛苦，因为每个数据库如果
even if you were you are working with
即使您正在与
the same time for example graph or a
同一时间，例如图表或
document it's different implementation
记录它的不同实现
has its own language its own way to work
有自己的语言和自己的工作方式
with so some people some smart people
有一些人有一些聪明人
has built this project this incredible
已经建立了这个令人难以置信的项目
project that is called Eclipse Gino Seco
Eclipse Gino Seco的项目
that's the main point is to have just
重点是
one framework to access different kind
一种访问不同种类的框架
of those sequel databases
那些续集数据库
so the main point forming points for
所以主要点形成
general Seco is to have a mapping API
山高将要拥有一个映射API
just one mapping API okay
只需一个映射API就可以
different maybe maybe path for each kind
不同的也许每种路径
of database but often in the same
数据库，但通常在同一数据库中
framework so for example if you are
框架，例如，如果您是
mapping a graph database you are mapping
映射要映射的图形数据库
the same way for in graph database that
在图数据库中的相同方式
you are losing can be Oracle can be
你输了可以是甲骨文可以
graph can be new for J or another one
图对于J或另一个可以是新的
that you like choose is also a
您喜欢选择的也是
communication API okay so in the
通讯API可以，所以在
framework you can communicate the same
您可以传达相同的框架
way and using the same API it brings no
方式和使用相同的API不会带来
locking so if you are not using anymore
锁定，因此，如果您不再使用
the specific way to write your queries
编写查询的具体方式
you are to write your searches your
你要写你的搜索
comments to put data to delete data or
注释以放置数据以删除数据或
whatever you are you are not having a
无论你是什么，你都没有
locking anymore and also another the
锁定了，也另一个
four point is to divide and conquer so
四点是分而治之
for example for each driver for each
例如对于每个驱动程序
kind of different databases they are
它们是不同的数据库
counting on the their own companies to
指望自己的公司来
write those drivers so for example
写这些驱动程序，例如
Oracle engineers is writing are writing
Oracle工程师正在写作
the the drivers for our crota base the
我们crota的驱动程序基础
neo4j engineers are writing the drivers
neo4j工程师正在编写驱动程序
for neo4j the same for Cassandra
对于neo4j，对于Cassandra而言相同
reiji's and so on and here we have this
reiji等等，在这里我们有这个
schema
图式
how do you know
你怎么知道的
works so we have the data access object
有效，所以我们有数据访问对象
on the top and we have Gino Seco working
在顶部，我们有Gino Seco在工作
in the mapping with the Artemis that is
在与阿尔emi弥斯的映射中
project that was brought to the protrude
突出的项目
inside the Juneau Seco framework and we
在朱诺山高框架中，我们
have the communication layer with Diana
与戴安娜有沟通层
another project that was brought to the
另一个项目被带到了
to the framework and down here we have
到框架，在这里，我们有
the in the data tire or in the top of
数据轮胎中或顶部的
the data tire all kinds of different no
数据轮胎各种不同的没有
secure databases which each one with its
保护数据库，每个数据库都有它
own implementation but all of them in
自己的实现，但都在
the same API communication mapping and
相同的API通信映射和
so in this in this way we have just one
以这种方式，我们只有一个
single solution for access different no
单一的访问解决方案
psycho databases and our description
心理数据库和我们的描述
here it's to bring the the Jacare to
这是将Jacare带到
meet Jane Doe Cisco and in this meeting
认识Jane Doe Cisco，并在这次会议上
happening in the cloud so we brought out
发生在云中，所以我们带出了
also discussion the cloud native a
还讨论了云原生
computer foundation and why because the
计算机基础以及为什么因为
CN CF has some kind of standards when we
CN CF有一些标准
are talking about cloud native
在谈论云原生
application and we can't build today
应用程序，我们今天无法构建
this kind of solution to our problem to
这种解决我们问题的方法
our developer in the city and with
我们在城市的开发商
technologies buildings accommodation we
技术建筑我们住宿
can't do it today without think about
今天想不到就做不到
cloud native application because our
云原生应用程序，因为我们
applications are born in today as the
应用程序诞生于今天
cloud native so what what's in CSS that
云原生，那么CSS中有什么
we need you to think about when we are
我们需要您考虑我们何时
building cloud native application
构建云原生应用
basically we can make sure here three
基本上我们可以确保这里三个
points first application should be
分数第一个应用程序应该是
continued rising so today we can think
持续上升，所以今天我们可以想到
about it as docker containers as a
关于它作为码头集装箱
kubernetes
Kubernetes
deployed applications this application
部署的应用程序
needs to be dynamically orchestrated so
需要动态编排，因此
again talk about kubernetes talk about
再次谈论kubernetes谈论
any kind of orchestration tools and
任何类型的编排工具和
should be micro service-oriented so we
应该面向微服务，所以我们
have ReadyTalk it here about micro
在这里有关于微型的ReadyTalk
profile so that's a bit of a chore to
个人资料，这有点麻烦
find to fulfill this approach from CN CF
从CN CF找到实现此方法的方法
has to deploy our application in micro
必须在微型环境中部署我们的应用程序
service-oriented way so yes our problem
面向服务的方式，所以是我们的问题
is solved here we use it we came from
在这里解决了，我们使用它来自
Jakarta to build a real live application
雅加达构建真实的实时应用程序
use major framework we can all have our
使用主要框架，我们都可以拥有
application built from Jakarta since the
自雅加达建立以来的应用程序
first line of code we also brought to
我们还带到的第一行代码
the party the no sequel database where
派对无续集数据库
we can have massive amount of data is
我们可以拥有大量数据
spreaded in different regions different
分布在不同地区不同
kind of non secure databases and
一种不安全的数据库，以及
different implementations and we have
不同的实现，我们有
also macro profile so our application
还有宏配置文件，所以我们的应用程序
here can have many macro servers being
这里可以有很多宏服务器
planted and spreaded and distributed in
种植，传播和分布在
architecture of this in a cloud native
原生云的架构
way of doing micro service of you doing
做您的微服务的方式
applications and then we can in this way
应用程序，然后我们可以通过这种方式
we can have our recommendation system
我们可以有我们的推荐系统
being built in a very successful way so
以非常成功的方式建造
thank you very much hope you enjoyed and
非常感谢你，希望你喜欢
we have here my way my contacts and you
我们在这里以我的方式与您联系
can reach me so thanks for watching bye
可以联系我，谢谢收看